<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>0xAsh</title>
    
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>FristiLeaks 1.3 Writeup</title>
        <description>
          
          FristiLeaks 1.3 is a VulnHub box that I used to prepare for the OSCP exam. It’s by far one of my favorite VulnHub boxes I’ve done, as it involves some fun and simple reversing/code analysis. It also involves practice hopping around and enumerating a Linux environment from the perspective of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-08-02-FristiLeaks-1.3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-08-02-FristiLeaks-1.3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kioptrix Level 1.3 (#4) Writeup</title>
        <description>
          
          Kioptrix Level 1.3 is the fourth iteration of the Kioptrix VulnHub challenges. It involves taking advantage of a SQL injection vulnerablility to login to a simple web application that leaks user credentials. Using these credentials we can connect to the box via SSH. Unfortunately, our SSH sessions spawn a restricted...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-29-Kioptrix-Level-1.3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-07-29-Kioptrix-Level-1.3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kioptrix Level 1.2 (#3) Writeup</title>
        <description>
          
          Kioptrix Level 1.2 continues the Kioptrix VulnHub series, and provides great experience creativily reusing credentials, attacking common web applications, and cracking hashed passwords. We start by exploiting LotusCMS to get a shell as www-data. From there, we find MySQL credentials that we use to login to phpMyAdmin and dump hashed...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-29-Kioptrix-Level-1.2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-07-29-Kioptrix-Level-1.2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kioptrix Level 1.1 (#2) Writeup</title>
        <description>
          
          Kioptrix Level 1.1 is the next box in the series of Kioptrix VulnHub boxes. This box ups the ante from its predecessor, beginning with a simple SQL injection exploit to gain access to a web console. The web console can be bypassed to execute code, which we use to get...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-28-Kioptrix-Level-1.1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-07-28-Kioptrix-Level-1.1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kioptrix Level 1 (#1) Writeup</title>
        <description>
          
          In preperation for my OSCP exam, I tackled a series of VulnHub boxes, Kioptrix Level 1 being the first. In retrospect, this box is really, really old. Like 2010 old, so it’s real-life applicability is questionable. It is a simple boot-to-root box that is vulnerable to a remote code execution...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-27-Kioptrix-Level-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-07-27-Kioptrix-Level-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
